uh or like your brain is really attuned
to those happy paths and what should we
call the non-happy path I keep I was
trying to unhappy path the unhappy path
the bad path the evil path the sad path
the sad sad path has a good ring to
[Music]
it best path of acing when you can just
you know critical
[Music]
things yeah dude
all righty my dude this I think is one
of my favorite episodes of the year
every year we just get 10 awesome pieces
of research Deep dive it figure out what
has been at the top of the web hacking
World in this past year it's it's a fun
one to record for sure yeah I mean it's
the highest total like value per time of
any episode I'd say yeah yeah for sure
um but before we and we got a lot to
cover we got a lot to cover and not a
lot of time to do it today so I'm not
sure if we're going to make our dead
that's in like an hour here or not um
but before we hop into it I got to say
man I have had my head deep in a bug
this week deep deep and I to be honest
actually so much so so much so that when
I message you my wife is like is Justin
okay she legitimately asked me to text
you and say just ask she said ask Justin
if he's okay dude I just you know
sometimes when you get a vul it's like
you just go go go at it like and and to
be honest it only normally happens
during live hacking events where I go
this deep right but this is the first
time in a while where I've been like I
will exploit this bug you know it
probably helped that last week you got
multiple like 10K bounties from them
right that that did help but but you
know you you go up against a Target and
you're like you know keep hitting wall
after wall after wall and but then you
just got to like make it happen you know
and and this was one of those times and
finally after like 30 hours messing with
this like it might be a high you know
like it's not even crit is it because of
user interaction is that why yeah yeah
well the user interaction is required
for sure um but it's like you know
there's just a a monstrous chain and a
new CSS it's a CSS injection and you
know of course and of course I had to
come up with like this new CSS uh
exfiltration technique that I'll
eventually post about um but man it
feels good it feels good to literally
what I did Joseph was I I took my phone
I took all of my notifications I just
said I'm putting it on do not disturb
until I solve this bug no way and I I
didn't look at any of the messages it
went across multiple days yeah dude
multiple days this is three days I
didn't touch a single notification or or
a single item on my to-do list it was
painful but I loved it and I got it and
I got the bug so you know that's amazing
I'm I'm gonna share it later in the
episode but I'll go ahead and give them
a preview right now that I think we work
in the best industry by far oh my go
it's for reasons like that right yeah
dude it's so it's so easy to like just
get lost in it you know once once I
allow myself to do it and and for the
past like a couple months I used to get
lost in a lot as a full-time Hunter
right um but for the past couple months
you know I've I've had critical thinking
I've had kaido stuff I've had all sorts
of stuff sort of pulling at me left and
right mentorship and um and man I felt
good to just put everything on do not
disturb and just say screw it I'm not
responding to anything until I I
complete this bug yeah do you think do
you think you would have eventually
popped it if you hadn't done that I
don't know dude I don't know I we
probably hit we probably hit four or
five different like ah we're done you
know walls uh on this bug and pushed
through um so I think I think it it
required the amount of focus that it got
and to be honest man maybe I'm a little
optimistic but I feel like most bugs are
that way where like after a while after
you kind of um you know I this is
probably just me being hyper confident
but like if if you put enough time and
effort into it you can kind of bend the
application to your will you know um I
don't know maybe that's too optimistic
we we're struggling with another right
now so we'll see see how that one pin
out maybe that's the case when you have
application and interconnected
applications that are as complicated as
Google does then maybe you're right
right but there are just some
applications that are so simple that
it's like if if there's no Gadget
there's no Gadget right yeah dude I
don't know we we did uh you know and
shout out to Integrity they Rock um but
when when they did the live hacking
event uh in in um uh Portugal last year
or maybe it was the year before um one
of the one of the pieces of scope that
they had was like real small and most
people were focusing on other things
because of that um and and I was like n
I'm going to focus on this guy you know
and and and after staring at it for long
enough I came up with this like wonky
you know client side path traversal
chain that that had some some actual
impact so yeah you know they there small
applications minimal scope you it's
disappointing sometimes but there's
something there there's something yeah
yeah I feel it all right well we got you
said not a lot of time yeah tight on
time but but before we get into it I do
want to hear about this AI blog post you
put out and and the master class you're
going to run on it because I I saw it
yesterday I skimmed it but with all of
the research that we needed to read for
this episode I didn't get to read it so
so tell me about yeah yeah I'll give
everyone the 30 second overview
basically I have been asked hundreds of
times to tell someone like to just
answer the question of how do I get
started with hacking AI stuff and I
think that there's also this huge um gap
of like basically bug Hunters that want
to be able to hack Ai and they're kind
of confused about what is AI safety what
is AI security and then you know what
security vulnerabilities can exist in
certain chat apps and and what kind of
interactions exist there and I wanted to
have like One deao Zero to Hero style
guide and I think there's going to be
you know tons more content like this as
as it goes on and I'll keep updating it
if there are any like new breakthroughs
or anything but I think at least for for
months and maybe for a year or two this
should be all you need to go from zero
to hero dude sick so yeah living
document yeah I am definitely going to
add to it as we go um especially some of
the tools that are coming out hatic is
dropping some cool stuff and one of hit
things but um yeah I'm doing a
three-hour master class on March 11th at
like 9:00 a.m. Pacific 12:00 noon
Eastern it's only 200 bucks I wanted to
make it super accessible it will be 90%
of the content from the blog so if you
can't afford it or don't care just read
the blog but there are a lot of people
who learn better better with like a you
know visual medium and then also
there'll be like live Q&A and I may talk
about a few bugs I found so sweet dude
that sounds awesome yeah I definitely
definitely need you know AI definitely
needed something like that where it's
just a kind of a Playbook to go after
those um I think it'll be really helpful
if you're using AI to help understand or
attack an application you can just copy
and paste a whole blog in there and then
use that as like the ID to basically
kind of teach the llm in that moment
what what you're trying to achieve using
AI to teach AI how to attack AI
yeah but but really though I mean I do
think like you know all of us love
copying and pting in context into into
these large language models right now
and I think it'll be perfect for that
one thing I did want to say was uh that
critical thinkers do have like a 50% off
code so for the for the teaching there
so maybe you can like pay $35 to save
$100 yeah exactly that's great that's a
good idea all right so with that let's
jump right into the content portager top
10 of 2024 um each year Port swigger uh
puts together a panel and takes
nominations for the top web research of
the past year and uh to be honest it's
one of my most uh anticipated blog posts
of the year I think because um it just
pulls together a lot of really good
resources even the nominations list is
like phenomenal um and then you know
what we do here at critical thinking is
we take that list and we digest each one
of them um and in the past actually uh
Joseph what we've done what I did with
Joel in the past was then we would then
provide our top 10 out of the top ranked
it reorder it I we didn't do that this
time I don't know if we'll fit that in
at the end we may like pause and then
deliberate or whatever but um uh the the
submissions this year were thank
goodness not as uh like cumbersome as
last year dude like last year I think
there were like four or five out of the
10 were like 50 page research papers oh
my goodness so Joel and I like sat down
and we had to allocate like 20 hours
yeah yeah more dude like it took
multiple days of prep to kind of get
through that whole episode y but dang I
learned so much um to to close the loop
do you know if they commented on if
anybody voted for that thing that said
do not vote for this oh I don't know I
don't know I'm sure they I didn't know
if they tweeted about it somewhere or
something yeah yeah but the to be honest
I looking at the top 10 this year um we
see an odd amount of like writeups like
like you know vulnerability writeups
rather than like this is a new uh uh
technique to attack applications um
which you know I'm not going to complain
about I love a good write up just as
much as anybody else um but I do think
that uh it would be cool to have a
research top 10 and a write-ups top 10
because there are some amazing writeups
out there that you that chain together
like a bunch of really just commonly
known and pretty rare gadgets to into a
beautiful Masterpiece um and then
there's stuff like you know James
kettle's HP request smuggling which
she's like here's a new vul class you
know um so do you think kind mix
together here do you think that uh that
means we'll have an an inordinate amount
of research this next year because if
you think about if there's a lot of
people who just didn't make the cut
right they didn't get the chance to
publish the research or what have you
and they were working on it the last
year it'll probably get published in
2025 so I would expect probably a
greater number of like kind of Novel
pieces of research this year [__] dude
every other year we're gonna have a 20
hour prep session for these Port soer
top 10 maybe so maybe so yeah maybe um
all right well let's dive right into it
um we kind of diced them up uh and
divvied them out um so I think I've got
one then you've got two then I've got
two so I'll go ahead and start with this
number 10 and we'll work our way down to
number one um and the the number 10 on
the list was hijacking ooth flows via
cookie tossing thank you for giving me
this one uh Joseph you know because we
kind of did the draft a little bit Yeah
and um and I was hoping I'd get this one
because I love to talk about cookies and
cookie tossing um and you know to be
honest this uh this write up is like a
pretty great primer on cookie tossing
and why it's awesome um the the author
sort of goes through and talks about
what is Cookie tossing how do cookies
work what are the the cookie attributes
um and for anybody who who isn't
familiar with uh with cookie tossing the
concept behind that is that when you set
a cookie you have the ability to set um
well first if you're not familiar with
it you're not listening to the Pod
enough because we've talked on about it
a lot um but in these attributes you
have the ability to specify a domain and
a path for this cookie okay the domain
is the domain to which the cookie will
be sent and the path is the path to
which the cookie will be sent well
there's this really awesome combination
that you can do where you set the domain
uh not to a subdomain like
www.google.com but to. google.com or
whatever right um and that will send it
to every subdomain of google.com and any
subdomain of google.com in this scenario
uh has the ability to set cookie like
that and they can also set a cookie with
a specific path now this this Joseph is
where the rub happens here this is where
I have a I have a quick question when it
when it comes to cookie tossing do you
normally actually have control of some
sort of parameter that's then
controlling it or is it like um
something different like you know what's
the mechanism by which you typically
can't control this it's typically you
know semicolon injection like there you
know you control the value of a cookie
right so me maybe there's some cookie
State equals and then you provide a
value via a query parameter and what
they're doing is they're taking that
that value and they're just putting it
you know directly into a cookie and
they're not checking for the semicolon
which is the what we've talked about in
the past and sort of deemed as partial
cookie injection where you control um
you can break out of the cookie value
context and go into the cookie attribute
context right um and and so if you do
that then you gain control of these
Primitives you know uh domain equals and
and path equals that allows you to
specify a specific domain and a path um
and the reason why that's interesting is
because you can make your cookie get
priority um meaning be sent first to the
web server by specifying a more specific
path for your cookie so let's say
there's two two cookie PR or two cookie
two State cookies right and one of them
has no path set and one of them has path
to uh you know yeah slapp or SL initiate
off right your your more specific path
even if the domain is wider is is going
to actually be given uh priority and and
that's sort of the whole concept be
behind this this cookie tossing research
um and you know the the author kind of
gives a couple scenarios where uh this
is this is helpful um one is in this
sort of uh SEF like situation so uh what
you can do with this so let's say you
got an accss on like blah blah blah
subdomain
the domain and specify a very specific
path now as the user is going around in
the application let's say that there's
like a update address function or
something like that right um and it's
there's no Cerf protections on it but
it's Json content type so you can't Cerf
it right um and you set your attacker
session cookie for that update address
path right y so when the user goes in
there to update their address and their
browser sends a request to the server
with their user data their address um
our cookie will be
will be attached to that request only
for that specific path so just for that
specific path the user is logged in as
the attacker yep and it will set it as
your address so you can view it exactly
exactly so you can e exfiltrate data
that way it's sort of like a c surf but
it doesn't actually happen to the
victim's account it actually happens to
your account but that's bad for the
victim you know sort of situation um and
this is a very very similar technique to
what uh was was discussed with maton um
in in episode gez had it somewhere this
likee I wonder if that exists anywhere
um when you're generating API keys
because that would be the most that
would be like kind of the coolest well
maybe it maybe it would only generate it
maybe it would only generate it for the
attackers off and so maybe it wouldn't
matter but um that feels impactful the
well and actually what what happened in
the article was sort of something
similar which was um linking a a GitHub
account um and so what they had a call
back where you you could link a a GitHub
account um you know to to your flow or
to to your uh account in the app and so
when you go through the flow and it
comes back and it links your account uh
that's when the attacker fixated their
session to that specific path so it
actually leaked the victim's GitHub
account to the attacker's account and
then you could access all their like
GitHub information right so there's lots
of cool ways to exploit this also of
course uh self xss as we talked about in
the episode with Monon um which we'll
Link in the description uh but
definitely really cool write up uh over
here from sneak and um there's a really
awesome YouTube video also that I just
tweeted out about it that's a really
good primary to cookie tossing so um if
any of you listeners are aspiring to
master the C cookie tossing technique
then I think that would be my go-to
resource um to check out yeah I had a
thought a minute ago that I forgot to
ask um is this something that is often
detectable in like a um a deterministic
way where you could have like a plug-in
Bido whatever that actually will just
highlight things where the cookie is
able no because you have you have to
find the vulnerability it would be like
it it would be like you need a
reflection like like the partial cookie
injection is definitely um detectable
you know you can check the quer
parameters and then if it's if it's and
then the set headers header yeah sorry
set cookies header yeah set cookies or
if it's but it can also happen on the
client side okay with document.cookie
right so it's it's a little bit tricky
to to get fully I think sure cool you
want to move on to the next one yeah
yeah take it away sweet yeah so the next
one is chat GPT account takeover and you
know I took this one just uh in the
theme of uh my career path
so so I I think I ended up taking it
second or third in the draft U the the
listeners will learn what I picked first
uh since you gave me first pick as we as
we go along but um yeah so This research
is from W what is actually the name how
do you pronounce that no I have no idea
dude no herel search security research
but it's really cool I actually wonder
if it made top 10 just because the word
chbd was in the title not it's fantastic
research I'm not saying that but just
you know where AI is like so popular I
wonder if people saw that and kind of
were more likely to vote for it but it's
really neat I think um honestly I
relearn cast deception like you know
twice a year I don't really use it much
and then when I read about it's like oh
yeah this how it works uh it definitely
feels like something that could be um
detected or at least highlight
by specific tools to find them I'm sure
lots of people have written those but
it'd be great if someone would write one
of those for kaido um and so yeah cast
reception for anyone um not up to speed
or in case we have some new listeners is
basically where you're like uh caches
are very very useful for loading static
content such as JavaScript files or
images or whatever stuff that's not
going to change and it's totally safe to
do so but anytime you are able to Cache
someone's data like someone else's data
or I guess you're always mostly going to
be cashing your own data at an endpoint
then someone else can browse there an
attacker can browse there or they can
kind of force you to click a link or
it's kind of like R xss where you click
a link it caches your data then the
attacker brows to that same link and
your data shows up because it's cached
and so this vulnerability exist anytime
a company is caching a a path or a route
or an endpoint that hosts sensitive data
when they shouldn't be and so you can
detect that with the header um you know
it's a for cloud flare specifically it's
cf-- status
but it's it's always called um hit as
usually the header H Hit or Miss is
typically what you see yeah yeah and
then you can see dynamic as well right
do you do you look for these much that
was one thing I was going to ask you was
whether you look for cash reception much
yeah I I um I haven't looked at it as
much I mean I've definitely reported you
know probably 10 of these uh on hacker
one uh in the past but I think it was
something that I was focused on a little
bit more back in like
2023 um and I haven't reported them
quite as much um over the past years so
it's something that I need to pay
attention to and I do think that since
it is something that's happening over
HTTP it is particularly well suited you
know without a lot of client side
interaction um I think it is
particularly well suited for like a
kaido Plugin or something like that to
sort of detect what could be going on
there um and there's definitely an
amazing uh set of research that came out
uh at Defcon this past year that we
covered in the Defcon episode uh from
the ports wiger research team on like
crazy ways to get stuff cached um so
that that definitely goes in in uh in
conjunction with this really well and
would be a good place for anybody who
wants to sort of get up toate on this uh
on this F Type does this happen uh so I
was going to ask you this as well I
didn't know if any in any of that
research they mentioned does this happen
as like a cloud flare misc config or
does this actually happen on the server
where they've written a piece of code
that determines where it gets cached or
determines what it gets cashed it's a
little bit of both sometimes you know
depending on the configuration but a lot
of times it's it's the the the
problem of the caching proxy uh so
whatever is causing causing the cach
you've got it it misconfigured in such a
way that it will cash you know based off
of URL exion with a wild card or
something yeah exactly and and so if you
you know one of the one of the most
common ones you'll see is like aspx has
this really liberal um path uh
delineations like it just if if you hit
whatever.
aspx abc. CSS then it always just is
like okay that's just ASX file you know
um and then if but it looks like that
file ends in CSS so the the caching
server is like all right I'll cash that
yeah um and so yeah and I think one of
the other things that mentioned in this
article was that this is actually really
commonly done with um path traversals as
well so the excuse me my throat just
gave out on me um so the author here
uses percent 2f do dot percent 2f in
this uh write up you know to to make it
look like the um path is actually under
SL share which should be a cachable
endpoint um but then proceeds to do the
path traval because the server is
processing percent 2f as a directory
delineator directory delimiter um and
that's what what sort of was able to
cause the the vulnerability to occur
yeah if someone wrote this um tool spe
like a tool specifically for this I
would say they should like always check
for
sljs percent 2f dot do percent 2f
because you know JavaScript files are
going to frequently be cached similar if
there's like a SL assets SL images do it
there as well and so you can kind of
check for all of those separate things
yeah so what they did was uh for this
they were able to cash um like Justin
just said it was caching shared content
so in chat GPT at least at that time you
were able to share a a you know a thread
or AI response and the links were always
like SL sharechat you ID and so they
were cashing everything there and I was
actually ask you is this considered
client side patch versal or just just a
standard one it's kind of weird it's
like it's more like a like a secondary
context thing right where where like
there's a um there is a server somewhere
along the line that's not the cache
server that is processing that percent
2f as a as a directory delimiter um and
that's why they're able to cause this
whole thing um yeah yeah that's fair
yeah yeah because like yeah the caching
server is not normalizing the path but
then the backend server is normalizing
it exactly and one of one of the things
that I think would be really cool from a
research perspective or somebody that
wants to make a Plugin or something like
that is to figure out a way to inform
hackers in a meaningful way what the
different application segments are and
what kind of headers are being respond
responded with in this area right
because the reason why this worked in
this scenario is because there's there's
caching um configured for the the SL
share you know section of of chat.
open.com um and so if there's if there's
a good way for us to sort of
understanding like oh okay over here
doesn't have coup headers over here
doesn't have extrem options headers over
here seems to be caching stuff that sort
of information is really valuable to uh
us and I think is not really formalized
in a way that's very readable at this
point yeah do you think that maybe some
sort of visualization based Plug-In or
software where like yeah you know as
you're hacking on a website it's like
kind of learning like you said the
different context and drawing it in just
like a very simple like you know TL draw
style thing where it's like this and
this yeah that'd be good that could be
cool and to be honest maybe it would be
even easier to do you could just say
like cash segments extreme options and
no extreme option segments and then
provide the like highest
level path that does not have that
header you know present in the response
and it's a little bit tricky because
like sometimes 404s have different
headers and you know but but it is
interesting for sure yeah well may maybe
it would only do it for um requests that
actually are exist in the sitemap so
then you don't have to worry about 404s
and 500s and that sort of thing because
like yeah I mean if you br Force set or
checked it then of course you would deal
with those issues but if you were just
looking at what actually exists in the
natural browsing history it would be
much more likely to be real um yeah so
so that little piece of patch veral
actually made it what's called a wild
card cash deception because you could
you could basically go to any path to
cash it um yeah and then they uh
reported it and this was uh shortly
after open AI started their bug Bounty
uh program and they paid 6500 for it all
right cool so what's this one next we
got oath non-happy path to atto you know
I'm actually really glad they put Happy
path in the title because that was one
of the coolest things that I took from
this rereading this I'm like man I just
love the idea of a happy path I think
it's something that we all mentally do
who've been in like the hacking game for
a little while it's like you have to
understand how that application works
normally so then you can understand when
things are kind of weird and that
understanding normally is actually a
really key piece and I think it's
probably a reason why spending a lot of
time on a single program
can often pay off because now you know
all of those happy paths and um you know
you don't always know what the NOS are
in application as Douglas Day always
mentions and I think by understanding
the happy path you can see all those NOS
pop out because your eyes are uh or like
your brain is really attuned to those
happy paths and what should we call the
non-happy path I keep I was trying to
unhappy path the happy path the bad path
the evil path the sad path the sad sad
path has a good ring to it so the sad
path makes the developers sad because
they have to pay us a bounty so um yeah
so when I was reading this one it's
called ooth non-happy path to atto by o
RX or o xrz and so um he was working on
a public bug Bounty program um it looks
like the Happy path yeah he calls it
non-happy paths the happy path and sad
path actually somehow or the happy path
comes from Wikipedia and he got the
non-happy path from our boy fron Rosen
right up so love it um probably dirty
dancing yeah it is dirty dancing so the
cool thing here that um there are a
couple fre you know key cool takeaways
we are have had an entire episode on
ooth so I'm not going to break all that
down again but I wanted to mention a
couple of these quotes um so one is I
tried changing the response type
parameter from code to ID token I don't
know if we covered that on that oo
episode U but I thought that was a
really uh cool technique and then they
mentioned later U because there's like
three different forms of ooth that this
app supported that
um that is not possible with GitHub with
login with GitHub and it's not possible
Facebook has this kind of interesting um
thing where you have to like click to
continue as the user which changes the
referr header so that ended up not being
exploitable either um and then kind of
the combination of using the ID and the
token thing here is that Google allows
you to pass multiple response type you
can do ID token or code or comma
separate them right they both work yeah
and then uh this actually it feels like
might be you know hx1 is a decent friend
of ours he hasn't made that much noise
lately but he's still doing buck hunting
I was talking to him recently he's found
a lot of issues in ooth with Google
logged in with Google implementations
and I wonder if this is why because kind
of some of the stuff they support from a
complexity perspective so with response
type ID token or comma or code you still
end up at a page where you as that we're
all familiar with where you select which
account to log into right which then
breaks the refer part of this of his
payload but um then this part this part
was something that I thought would be
really highly valuable to all of our
listeners if you use prompt equals none
as a
parameter um then users who are
previously logged into Google it
bypasses that page and I think just logs
you in with your primary absolutely
which I never knew you could even do
that yeah that's a super useful Gadget
I've used that many times okay well
maybe maybe it's much more common for
for the for the I we you know you see it
at live hacking events or like I've kind
of done a couple deep Dives on o before
but it it is it is super helpful and I
think the the changing the response type
also like cuz if I'm if I remember
correctly it ends up in a fragment still
right it doesn't end up in a in a like a
query parameter um with when you provide
multiple of those those values there at
least it possibly can um which is super
helpful for being like okay well I still
need the code because that's how I
redeem it on the application but I I
want it in a different format so it's
not consumed as soon as it comes to the
page and th it's in the fragment why
would they ever support Comm upar
response type I have no idea okay
because because like when I was reading
this I'm like I'm why that that feels
like just something Google should fix
because it seems like even using the
analogy of happy path really powerful
way to explain this basically even if
there are multiple happy paths like you
would never want a user to be able to go
down two pass at once it doesn't make
any sense for logging in it's like
you're logging in one way or you're
authenticating a different way you can't
do both at once and Google's like n you
can do both at once yeah yeah I'm not
really sure what what use there is for
that because typically you're swapping
the code anyway for a token um on the
server side so um yeah not sure what's
going on there but it is definitely a
helpful Gadget and and can help you map
out those unhappy paths for or sad paths
or whatever we're calling them for for
oath flows which is very helpful for
getting ATL yep sweet that is all I had
if you want to roll us into number seven
sweet dude all okay we we're D all right
we're doing it we're making pretty good
time this you know I think I I I I kind
of was like all right got to be ready
Joseph it's going to be a big episode
get ready because last year was so
intense but I think this year with a lot
of write-ups it's it's mostly just sort
of covering the the main takeaways from
the vulnerabilities and then kind of
moving into the next one so yeah and on
top of that I think it helps that we've
covered so many of these I don't know
maybe that was something you all did
last year but maybe it was less so yeah
dude we've covered I think we've covered
like at least seven out of 10 of these
yeah over half for sure yeah so speaking
of that we covered uh this number seven
which is arbitrary JavaScript execution
in pdf.js um we covered that in episode
72 so if you want to go back and kind of
get a little bit more of a deep dive on
that you can um but the the TDR of this
writeup is that uh the author is
providing a a PDF to a library called
pdf.js which I believe is the um default
Library used in Firefox MH to render
PDFs if you just open it up in your
browser and um I think this is a really
cool technique a really cool um way to
kind of go a little a layer deeper um by
by working with a a file type that isn't
like typically considered to be web
stuff you know you got like HTML SVG you
know XML or whatever um and some all
these web types um but PDF is something
you kind of think of more as a file and
it kind of goes in there and analyzes
how this this JS library is parsing that
out um at a lower level uh which I think
is is very applicable takeaway for
anybody who wants to do research um and
what he kind of stumbles upon is that uh
this pdf.js sometimes it relies on um
the browser to render specific fonts but
other times um the the pdf.js is
responsible itself to render these
glyphs and let me explain what a glyph
is really quick a glyph is a uh a path
that should be drawn to represent a
character right so um you know if you're
doing an i the path will have like a
little dot at the top and then it'll
have a space and then a you know a line
if it's a lower lowercase eye um and
that is represented by you know however
the specific font represents that um and
pdf.js is responsible for rendering
those cliffs in some scenarios and so
what it did to do that was it would
create a JavaScript function which would
render that specific glyph um and and
and when it did that it passed uh a
piece of the PDF that you that you
supplied um into the new function um
call right new space function and then
you you kind of call it uh which is the
function object Constructor um which is
essentially
eval uh if that function gets
called and so this is I think is an
underrated sync uh new function and who
knows whether it's being used very very
often but um you know the parameter you
pass into that is just raw JavaScript
code and then it gets kind of could we
do a can we do a GitHub search to find
out if it's used like in like open
source stuff yeah I'm sure it'd be all
over the place and it's just one of
those ones that's just not very
high-profile you know um so that's that
was one takeaway for me um and the other
takeaway was uh sort of got from this
quote it said if we instrument the uh
pdf.js code to log these generated uh
function objects then we can see so on
and so forth right so it's clear here
that they have set up a an environment
where they are debugging this which is
not very hard to do in the browser when
you're dealing with JS libraries right
you you've got Dev tools all set up you
don't have to worry about hooking into
like a debug or anything like that the
JS uh engine is already you know
debugged by Dev tools um and it's just
cool that they are you know making sure
that those break points are set and kind
of jumping into this and when when you
go back and you look at it it's like wow
this is so simple you know um but it it
definitely took that extra mile of like
let me identify this non-traditional
sync and sort of Trace through all of
this pdf.js code to see where um the the
sync is used yeah two quick things one
Speaking of Dev tools you just did a
master class for critical thinkers so if
anybody hasn't watched that they can go
watch it or sign up and go watch it if
they're not currently one um but on the
second thing I was curious so does this
execute in the context of the web page
so if they're browser if they're
rendering it is it going to actually
execute with full control of the cookies
of the page that's loading it yeah it is
and and and when you open up a local um
PDF as well uh this is in Firefox then
it will execute with the file handling
um yeah I saw that what access do does
the file Handler have it's it's got a
lot of stuff I think there were some
some things uh that were a little bit
different here let me see if I can jump
in here interestingly enough this is not
a file path you see in the URL bar if
you're download the file instead pdf.js
runs under the origin resource pdf.js
okay so it's a resource file this
resents access to local files but is
slightly more privilege in other aspects
for example it is possible to invoke a
file download even to download arbitrary
file URLs um so it's it's a pretty
privileged context that this executed in
inside of Firefox um so very cool that's
kind that's kind of neat because I feel
like I when I read this and especially
as we were talking about it I'm thinking
like oh if there's a website that has a
pdf.js that's rendering the PDF like
that's where the vulnerability is but
this is interesting because if you have
file upload on a company's website or
whatever and generally and if the
application itself is like commonly
using PDFs you know like let's say
you're a shipper and you're uploading
shipping labels or something right if
you uploaded a malicious one where
employees would download and then open
especially right there in Firefox that
they're already using this have some
pretty big impact I wonder did they say
yeah it's a cve so it was it was fix
unfortunately but you know in Firefox if
they're using an older version of
Firefox it definitely could be impactful
um sure or if you find or if you find
something similar in a different library
or what have you so yeah the the other
thing here is like when you're when
you're looking at this right up it the
way that they outlined the code is
really clear and I'm sure it was like
fiscated and had a bunch of like other
stuff surrounding it but the way that
they output this um this code block is
like wow yeah that seems like a
vulnerability um uh but one of the
things that would have caught me up a
little bit is like they pass an integer
into this into this function right um a
function Constructor and that gets
passed as an integer into the the
resulting function um and they needed it
to be a
string um for for it to go into the
JavaScript like that uh and be be
rendered as a variable and why don't you
why don't you share your screen just
sure I know that production loves us to
do that a little bit more and that F
that font Matrix code uh block there is
like pretty neat oh yeah for sure let me
let me do
that okay um so down here down here at
the bottom right here you can see um the
this is the output of the function right
here here this c. transform and there's
integers being passed into this which
originate from this font Matrix thing um
but originally it looked like let's see
if I can find the one originally it
looked like this right um so these were
all integers uh being passed in um and
for them to one of the things that would
have caught me up a little bit is that
inside of the PDF I'm like ah how do I
even render a string um and apparently
in PDF strings are rendered with um
parentheses uh not double quotes So
this uh parentheses Fu bar here that
ends up getting put inside the the the
function body is this is the
representation of a string inside of uh
you know PDF language um right and so I
just like how they sort of went deep in
on this uh this whole PDF um structure
and understood all the various
Primitives and types that they have um
and then utilized that and the
difference between that and and the
JavaScript code here um to to get a
really crazy bug that was really
reminiscent of a of a like flash related
vulnerabilities and stuff like that yeah
that's interesting I'm sure they've
probably looked into it but I'll be
curious if this exist and like other
functions in here yeah yeah for sure um
this one number six is called double
clickjacking a new era of UI redressing
um and dude like we've covered this on
the podcast before I kind of love this
research but it's kind of like a little
meh I don't know so first let let me
just start by saying if you click on the
link to go to this website um which will
link in the description at the at the
very top of that page and I'll I'll
share my screen now um at the very top
of that page there's this uh little bar
right here right where you can press
play and hear a podcast generated by
notebook
LM explaining this whole flow and dude
we're cooked we're cooked man it's a
good podcast like I was sitting there
reading through it and listening to it
and I'm like
oh my gosh this thing is so good yeah I
do a little bit of AI Consulting for
businesses to help them know how to
implement it Ai and that's like the the
biggest thing that blows their mind so
I'm just like going through it and then
I say oh and by the way I generated this
podcast about your company and what you
sell and what you do and they start
listening to it and they're like wait
what it's like I I really wish that
Google would release how they do such
great like speech or text to speech
where it sounds so natural the podcast
hosts sound like completely real yeah
they hand off back and forth It's it's
like it's pretty crazy so 're definitely
cooked yeah exactly so anyway that was a
little scary but uh after I moved past
that and and uh you know came out of the
fetal position you didn't double click
the play button I did I would never
double click anything I would never
double click anything ever again um
because what this research is talking
about you see you see that transition
that was a good transition there um is
how you can Harvest double clicks
essentially to uh perform SE surfs uh W
within an application so um we covered
this on the Pod a little bit before so
I'm not going to spend too long on it
but as a refresher for you guys um the
flow of the the you know attack sort of
goes like this and this this by the way
is sort of what I'm talking about when I
say security research right like this I
think is more security researchy than
some of these writeups that that are
here even though the writeups are like
mind-bogglingly good because this is a
new attack right um and so anyway how
this works is you get two windows open
so that requires one click anyway right
you click to open a button um and now
you're you're in the the second tab uh
and as as the second tab you have the
reference to opener and you can redirect
opener to a page that will have negative
impact on the user if one button is
clicked on that page um the traditional
example for this one that he uses in the
blog post is like an uh authorization
endpoint where you're saying like yeah
I'll install this app on my Shopify
store or like yeah I authorize you know
this user to have all my data um and
it's just accept and then you do that
and it's done right um and so then what
the what the attacker does is you know
they pop up a capture or whatever and
say hey double click here to uh incur
you know to bypass the the capture and
and so on the mouse down event which is
the first thing that happens when you're
clicking um it closes the window and
then you've got sort of like a little
like a beat of the mouse up right and
then when you press down again for the
for the second aspect of the double
click now you're you're focused on the
window that was uh the opener of the
window that you were intending to click
on um which has now been redirected to
that uh that app um does it actually
happen that fast in a lot of apps like
the that the first window receiving the
command from the second window reloads
on this new authorization page fast
enough that the second click happens
quick it's not it's not a Reload thing
because what what's that's why you need
two tabs open so as soon as you're in
that second tab you redirect the first
tab to got it so it's waiting it's just
sitting there waiting fully loaded ready
to go right so and then on the on the
attackers tab you know you put the
double the button they need to double
click you put it right at the correct
index oh of course so that like as soon
as you close the page they're hovering
their Mouse is sort of hovering right
over the approve you know or accept
button um and then it's just really
funny thinking that like slow computers
where Chrome is most of the ram when
they click the button to close the first
tab it takes their computer like 3
seconds for the tab to close so the
second thing still happens on the first
Tab and nothing you know I'm running
like 128 gigabyte server that I'm
talking on right now and it still does
that sometimes I don't know tab it just
hangs for a second yeah yeah yeah it's
nuts um but but it's a cool technique
and and Co yeah and I and I think um you
know as far as takeaways from this go
because we're trying to give technical
takeaways for each of these um the the
technical takeaway is that uh whenever
there's like one single point of failure
one click is a single point of failure
in an application um this is a technique
that could be used and yeah so is is the
first Gadget something like client side
like post message that that would is
like like what what enables the attacker
to load that second page with the
reference back to the first it's just
window. open so so like you on an
attacker controlled page like you do a a
wind you get a click you know and that
does a window. open so now you've got
two attacker controlled Pages open right
and then you redirect the first one to
the victim site which you could do yeah
yeah which you can do because it's all
they have to do is be logged into the
app that you're trying to attack there's
no other Gadget that you need besides
like one click to to take over an
account right um wow so it's pretty
impactful and what he says is most have
chosen to address it while some have
have not you know that's a quote from
the article is saying like these
companies have typically accepted this
report and addressed it in one way or
the other now what he didn't say is I
got is there wallet connects is there
wallet connect for one push for one
clicks you're laughing no I'm being dead
serious that's where the most impact is
spinning right now well no no one you're
right I didn't realize that double click
jacking required basically nothing other
than the fact that there's like a state
CH or an important thing that requires
you to click through but that's really
common these days because your browser
already has like a session for Google
and a session for GitHub and a session
for Discord because you're like long
lived across all of them exactly so
there are so many things that are one
click to connect yeah so it just it's
kind of surprising to me yeah 100% I
mean to be honest like typically
something that requires one click and
then a double click I would be like
that's a little bit I don't know like as
far as user interaction required goes
but I mean the impact is there you know
like and it's who isn't going to do it
who doesn't double click on a caption
you know if it's says double click here
right it looks like especially if it
looks like the cloud flare one you know
the one that pops up where it's just
requires one click yeah if they change
it to double click it would not surprise
me in the least oh 100% um so anyway the
other thing I really liked about this
one was he did provide a pretty
reasonable method to prevent this from
happening which is on your single point
of failure pages right um You should dis
disable all buttons unless a mouse move
event has occurred because there's no
mouse move event when you're double
clicking right you just are on that page
and you're clicking there's no movement
um so it's a pretty actionable thing to
put on a page that's pretty high impact
from a security perspective to your
organization so I could definitely see
some companies addressing this and um
and and actually paying out a bounty for
it yeah yeah honestly that would
probably help with some of the a
automation based stuff too just like
detect real users yeah so all right um
so the next one got three in a row by
the way so yeah so sort of but we're
actually going to skip this one the the
number five is um exploring the D purify
Library by Kevin Mizu and we literally
just did a whole episode on this like
two weeks ago with Kevin yeah with Kevin
it's not like you and I covered it no
you had the author two hour long episode
uh with the man himself so go listen to
episode uh 111 if you want to get to it
and I will say it's a little bit of a
cop out uh because uh on that episode we
technically covered the second article
and this is the first article
um but I think the second article is
more applic for bug Hunters anyway and
this is another scenario where it's like
here's a write up of a bunch of
vulnerabilities in Dom purify um which
is is great and definitely you know an
amazing write up um but it's not like
here A bunch of techniques that you can
use to to attack an application that are
um you know a new vulnerability class or
something like that um what I will say
however Joseph is that after looking at
Don purify for two hours with Kevin in
that epis and kind of Thoroughly
understanding how the flow of of HTML
sanitizers go by reading this blog post
and his second blog post yeah I found
myself a lot more interested in HTML
sanitizers so like I recently have an
HTML injection it's but it's like you
know a benign HTML injection on a Google
page and I was like H well let me just
take a look at like how this sanitizer
is working right and I go in there and
I'm figuring out like oh these are the
attributes I have access to these are
the tags I have access to you know what
name spaces are these all in you know
like how are these attributes being
parsed and processed is there any um you
know replacement that's happening post
sanitization that could allow you know
these attributes or name spaces to
change um where the uses of Rex versus
like you know built-in browser um Dom
parsing functionalities so um there
there's there's there's a lot of stuff
that that can be learned from that and
uh the the Dom purify writeups uh will
really help you address HTML sanitizers
from a higher level um by looking at a
case study of how Kevin does that
specifically for Dom jfy yeah actually I
think that I have in my notes I even
think I sent it to you once I'm going to
pull out my notes right now like just my
own bug bunny notes um I think I had a
list of the different um ways that a
comment in HTML parsers could
be um could be parsed and I had like a
list of payloads that I may have sent
you yeah I still have my conversation
from to Ryan X the healthy Outlet right
here and um I I think I clean this up
but uh yeah I'll send this to you and
then also we can drop it in the in in
the show notes or in the CT in the
critical thinker chat later send it over
we'll find somewhere to put it sweet
just because I think that gives users
something really nice especially when
you're talking about a what you seek is
what you get editor you can paste all
these in there as one block and then
just like if any of them Parts weirdly
it's almost like a single payload in the
same way you would look for like an xss
polyglot very nice yeah there's like
those those xss payload lists as well
you just paste them in you're like oh
that was weird that's the one I'm going
to investigate exactly yeah all right so
number four worst fit hit me with it
Joseph yeah well I was gonna say I
appreciate you giving me first pick
because I went for this one I do have to
know would you have picked it oh yeah
dude yeah this a great one this is
awesome okay I feel like it's the
coolest one I feel like this should have
been number one but maybe maybe I just
love uh Transformations yeah so you know
if anyone is listening and they haven't
read Orange's worst fit research you
need to go read it right now just search
for worst fit which is you know such a
cool name too cuz the algorithm is
called uh best fit right mhm that's
right um so anyways I appreciate Justin
give me first pick because I picked this
one immediately um have you since
researching this have you used these
anywhere like have you looked for oh you
have yeah I actually have gotten it to
work too yeah it was it was amazing
popped a bug with it yeah yeah I did it
was super cool and and uh yeah the did
you use the Y did you use the Y sign
mapping yeah dude it's like so cool when
it works too dude oh my God the need
yeah that's sick yeah I uh I'm excited
about this um you know people obviously
know you have a lot of connection to to
Japan what people may not know is that
I'm kind of connected to Korea because
we have two two two of our kids two of
our three are adopted from South Korea
um so that's pretty sweet and actually
this is actually a crazy story I'm gonna
tell it and burn the extra 30 seconds
because everyone will think it's really
interesting go for it um my son who is
six years old actually you might not
even know this story Justin it's kind of
crazy
uh was a part of this promotion when he
was in Korea before he was adopted
called letters from Angels where they
bring K-pop celebrity stars and pair
them with the babies and have them pose
for a photo shoot and Samuels was not
only picked as the baby but then his
photo was like on the front of Marie CLA
magazine dude and was shown on like on
the news and on TV in Korea and uh the
way we found out it's really funny too
my wife was just like in like a Facebook
group for like
fames from Korea yeah his name is Kong
Daniel so if anyone knows he like won
the what's it called he won like the
American Idol for Korea like this was
you know five years ago whatever um and
so there's a picture of naked Samuel on
the front of Marie CLA magazine and on
and on the Marie Clair Instagram dude
that's like all the internet and stuff
if I can uh I don't know if I want to
share a link we'll see but people can
find it now it's on the internet yeah so
maybe we can just maybe we'll just share
that's that's GNA be great someday you
know when he's got a girlf friend you're
like hey check out check out this
picture of it he's like Dad shut up it
is the coolest uh you know random fact
like two truth and a lie yeah oh yeah oh
my gosh yeah that's hilarious I was on
front of a of a magazine as a baby wow
yes exactly uh here okay I'm gonna share
my screen even though this is not about
the episode at all okay screen what's
going on yeah we like we're like oh yeah
this is gonna be a tight episode and
then we we go down these rabbit ch dude
what is that amazing that's amazing dude
wow so cute yeah so anyways
uh my my my whole point is that I didn't
know that there was like a k that the w
symbol so for the like obvious the yin
symbol is the symbol for the main
currency in Japan but that the one
symbol which is the main symbol for
currency in Korea is also a potential
worst fit so I'm going to start using
that now and then once after there the
needle I'll let you know but um yeah so
if anyone has like just is wanting to
jump straight to what's the most
interesting what's the biggest payoff
here obviously Ori found a ridiculous
you know level of impact with all these
vulnerabilities in a bunch of different
ways um but one of the uh like kind of
the tldr is that you should be using
these four symbols there is the full
width double quote which toggles quote
Mo like like basically navigate between
places where quotes are often used to
truncate strings or things like that um
and that is code Point U ff02 then
there's the yign which will sometimes
map to whenever it's in best when it
goes to the best fit algorithm to
backslash and then the one sign which is
the you know the Korean money symbol we
were just talking about it also maps to
backslash and so both the ins sign and
one sign and then the full width
backslash can all be used to escape
quotes or alter syntax so yeah um yeah
Justin you guys it's it's it's pretty
crazy dude you know I I have been using
the double quote for a while because
like I don't know if you've got your
keyboard set up for Korean or how it
works for that but like I've got my
keyboard I can just like press uh
Windows key space and it converts my my
keyboard to like Japanese and then I can
type in Japanese and so it's it's very
easy for me to just be like all right
hop into full width characters throw in
the double quote you know and push it
through and I've actually been doing
that with uh like less than signs and
greater than signs as well and they they
do pop sometimes um so so that's
definitely like an easy thing to do just
copy and paste them in um so dude why
exactly do the like why does a double
width or why does a full width double
quote even exist like couldn't they just
have used a normal double quote there
yeah you know I don't know when when I
switch into the Japanese mode on my
keyboard it like all of the characters
are double width and like so for example
if I hit a it'll show me the Japanese
character ah right but if I hit R it'll
show me a full width uh R you know Roman
character R and then I can either press
o or U to make do or the the Japanese
you know um letters um and so I don't
know I think it's got something to do
with like those just already being in
like Unicode mode for input but it makes
it really easy for me to just put in
like full width double quote uh and and
all that sort of stuff because I'm
already sort of in that Unicode
environment yeah so if you're topping on
like a string and like the the text of
the string is Japanese is it like full
width double quote then then all the
Japanese characters and then full width
double quote again is that kind of how
it looks like on a web page or something
yeah yeah it'll render as a fullwidth
double quote even on the page so it's a
different it's a different code Point um
uh which is cool and is where this this
this comes into becoming a problem when
it when it doesn't fit uh when the best
fit matching is like a sensitive
character like a double quote or
backlash and and the one that I've had
the most success with so far is the
whole like forcing the page to get
rendered as a uh as
a like Japanese uh character set and
then the backslash becomes the end sign
and then you can just sort of Escape out
of the the JavaScript because backlashes
aren't backslashes yeah so that's pretty
cool that's cool yeah that is cool it
makes me just I mean again amazed and
I'm sure that everyone thinks about this
all the time but just Unicode has caused
so many security issues if there was
like a standard character set such that
that never was invented it would have
been so much better for a security
perspective because even with all the AI
stuff with the with the piece I just put
out right like I included two tools that
I put on my blog that you can go get to
from the tools page and they're both
Unicode related one is invisible Unicode
tags and the other one is like Unicode
Emoji variation selectors and so both of
those are ways to basically encode you
know a bunch of invisible information on
the page so anyways yeah pretty crazy
stuff we we did cover this one also in
more depth on episode 103 so if you want
to go back and and listen listen to that
one if you want more information on this
sweet um all right number three
unveiling te. HP request smuggling dude
I'm glad you chose this one because I I
don't know man request smuggling I found
it only like three or four times yeah
and it's it's just one of those
vulnerabilities that I'm like I've seen
I've I understand how it works I just
don't hunt for that and it and it's
crazy because almost every life hacking
event someone comes with in with a crit
from request sping yeah it it does feel
like it expanded the scope of the types
of vulnerabilities to a much greater
scale whenever this like set of
vulnerabilities came out because it can
be present in so many different
libraries and in so many different
configurations um and yeah so I think in
general one of the coolest things that
they did here was basically look at all
the existing um smug request smuggling
techniques and they ask the question
like why not this other variation right
um and so the exact quote
is right here
they said the idea however we eventually
asked ourselves why is there no te Dozer
I'll actually share my screen so that
the listener or that the viewers yeah
because there's like te doct and ct. te
or whatever but why not te. zero right
so there's content link transfer and
coding transfer and coding and then um
transfer and coding content length and
then transfer and coding transfer coding
but then the content length which is
treated the back back end ignores
content length header which is then
treated as zero but the front end parses
it with cl0 so it's kind of like why not
do te Z which is just you know a cool
idea and then um uh did you notice that
the thing they use to spin this up and
I'm sure that we talked about it U or
you all talked about it back whenever HP
Garden yes so it like you know we've
talked a lot recently about how it's so
easy to spin up little things using AI
like to have it right Docker files or
whatever but this is just a full force
multiplier in that regard oh yeah dude
this thing is amazing I I definitely
have seen this a couple times I haven't
used it yet but I think I mentioned it
um right on the episode right after I
met the guy that wrote it at a Google
Live hacking event and uh it was
hilarious because he was just like and
if you look at the read me you'll you'll
see what he's you know what it's like
here but he was just like uh catting
just sending data with print F directly
into netcat and that was how he was
attacking web servers right he wasn't
using a proxy or anything he was just
like print f netcat and uh and then if
you look at the the um the you know read
me on this thing they're doing something
very similar so it's very interesting
yeah really cool stuff I specifically
think that um research has all of a
sudden become accessible to a ton of
people that it wasn't accessible to
before with AI um I was talking with
Kevin Mizu to kind of like tie a bunch
of threads together about um some
different ways to do prompt injection
vulnerability specifically Al some ways
you could potentially get xss if you can
have a large language model reply with
like a really janky uh like um markdown
image link and so he claims he had he's
like found this like it definitely works
in some in some scenarios I was not able
to replicate it but the thing that I'm
bringing up was it took me like five
minutes in cursor to just ass on it to
give me an example like I like you know
make me an example HTML page with um you
know fake a respes that are basically
like this payload specifically and I
gave it the payload he had talked about
where like you use you like Escape some
um you kind of make like a fake image
markdown link where you escape some
stuff and you give like an onair alert
as a part of the payload and um and I
said but use like three or four of the
most popular mark down image render um
libraries so that I can test all of them
across to see which ones actually uh pop
like which ones and in like five minutes
or well maybe less than five minutes it
just wrote the HTML page and it wrote
The Python script and then and so I was
able to just open the HTML page in my
browser and then I was able to see what
the output from that llm fake llm output
would be had I gotten an llm to respond
with it and um that's and that hit me
with with this in the same way is it's
like if you have this idea so like I'm
gonna go ahead and apply to what we're
just talking about we were talking about
worst fit right we were talking about
those Japanese characters the the onean
character the Yen character and then the
two back SL or the double quote and then
the backslash you could just ask guy to
basically um say hey I'm looking I'm
trying to do some novel research and the
area of the of these parsers give me the
you know I want you to render these four
characters with the top five Python
parsers and the top five JavaScript
parsers and the top five pH PHP parsers
and put it all on a single HTML page
where I can see if they do anything
weird you know and you just like that's
crazy man like you can do so many cool
things like that today and I think that
um people should do that so it's just
all natural language too you don't have
to worry about any of these config files
and stuff like that but HP guarding kind
of does that for us already exactly yeah
my whole point there was like HTP guard
makes that even easier because it's
going to like stand up a bunch of
example HTTP servers that will you know
handle it differently
um yeah I did think that Google's Bounty
was kind of lame um since this was
actually this was vulnerable across like
you know a thou a couple thousand or
something um like the the root cause of
this one the te zero was it was
vulnerable on a bunch of different bug
bount platform or programs but the root
cause was actually that there was a um
Google gole either I AP and no they were
all either in gcp or Google I AP and it
resulted in these these vulnerabilities
and Google's pretty good about paying
out of stuff with like big impact and
they paid 8,500 for this but I would
have expected something that was like
cross a bunch of different um
organizations and a bunch of different
tenants to have paid more from
them yeah 100% I I wonder I wonder what
happened there I think it does get a
little bit difficult to show impact on
these sort of things sometimes when
you're not sure how the is actually used
but um definitely you know I don't know
in my my past exper experience Google's
been more than fairis with bounties but
I would have thought this one would
definitely be well into the five figure
range yeah and I think we had a similar
um comment from the critical thinkers
like I think a critical thinker or two
had a you know poor experience with with
Google I think a lot of it depends on
what you're reporting where you're
reporting and then how you're articulate
yourself right I mean yeah yeah we're
pretty good about articulating ourselves
and we also aren't hunting on like
really tiny sandbox things or what have
you but yeah yeah another one of the
members in the full-time Hunter Guild
got a 75k bounty though from Google and
got a um it was a 50k Bounty and then a
25k bonus for a well-written report yeah
which is just nuts that they like this
is one of the most well-kept Secrets I
think of the Google V vrp like just look
at the the about section and go into the
rules and scroll down to like
exceptional report and just say like hey
you need to include these two sections
root cause analysis and um uh
remediation steps and if you if your
report contains those two and it's a
good report then now it's an exceptional
report and now your Bounty is 1.5x and
I'm like whoa who wouldn't do that yeah
everyone's gonna do that that's crazy
well and that also makes their Bounty
payouts like so much crazier right
because they're already good but the but
1.5 exit and it's like whoa you know do
you know if they still do that I was
going to mention this to you your
vulnerability that you just found that
you don't think will pay out that much
um where it's like a crazy chain with
like five different you know blockers it
would probably make for an amazing write
up they used to do like these huge
bonuses for like really good write-ups I
I feel like they discontinued it yeah
they would reward the top five writeups
of the year for Google bounties my my
buddy found I think like a 10K bug or
something he's not a Bug Hunter so it
was really cool that he that he like uh
found this and submitted it but his ride
up got second overall and so he got like
a $75,000 bonus so I remember him just I
remember him being like flabber $5,000
bonus yeah I think first gets 125 or 150
they're they're very generous in that
regard let me do they might not do it
anymore but best write ups
Google go dude I I'm gonna put more
effort into my reports if that's the
case are reports it's the write up like
they they I think they want the
publicity of it it's not the they want
you to do a write up on the buck yes
yeah yeah it has to be a public write up
on the buck yeah hey I can do that I
could I got a podcast you know like like
people will read it probably
yeah jog. criticalthinking podcast. yeah
wow very cool man I didn't know that I
gotta I gotta talk to Sam and Martin
about that because that would like that
yeah so it was called 2021 gcp vrp prize
I'll share my screen so you can see it
it's the cloud which is now in scope uh
they they they have like their own
official bug bount team it's like in
really great scope I shared the wrong
thing yeah they Rock too I I submitted a
little bug to them recently and got like
this huge they're listening so uh shout
out to y'all thank you for that that
really awesome response on their report
they were like hey you know tell the
team I said I said hey um so they
definitely listen to the Pod but here
I'll move it over here yeah sorry I'm
got to pull up we can cut out this I got
a little pop up here that says Joseph
ther's browser needs screen sharing
permission so oh weird um yeah so dude
check this out what yeah so this is 2021
I assume it happened after this or maybe
they just continued it but yeah look
give first oh my gosh uh this so this is
just for the write up so this is like
just to encourage security you know free
churcher just to focus on
gcp um no way 133k for first prize
73 third prize this is my buddy my buddy
Mike no way third third and second prize
both get
73k
yeah my God for for just writing a good
blog that's what's crazy but anyways wow
well definitely going to Su that I got
to talk to the team about that um all
right did you have anything else on
on te. zero request smuggling or is that
is that Prett much tldr sir let's jump
to the top two okay um so I guess hold
on let's go back to that take away from
that is is what you know easy to spin up
testing environments use your brain when
looking at not just use your brain
Listen Justin this is a good practical
tip when you're when you're looking at a
let's say a set of payloads a set of
functionality a set of connection types
right you want to to make sure that
you're comprehensive in the different
permutations you can get right yeah
you're thorough right yeah so basically
they noticed that this look at request
smuggling originally wasn't thorough it
did not consider te. Zer maybe it did
and you know who knows sh out the port
team's amazing right I mean I'm sure
they considered it maybe they just
didn't find anything that was
exploitable in the moment or something
um they're busy changing the world so I
mean yeah I think that's the key point
right is like think about all the
different happy paths or sad paths that
can exist and make sure you test them
all and don't just assume that because
one wasn't mentioned or one wasn't
exploited yet that it was not
exploitable true true I like that okay
cool all right let's let's go to the
number two here and then I'll let you
take it away with number one um number
two D this one was kind of the craziest
I don't know this was crazy like when I
was reading this I was like Wow uh
really blown away and I think it was an
interesting comment that they had in the
um the top 10 uh list I think James said
something along lines of like kind of
crazy that uh this didn't get first
place this year it just shows how how
you know intense the competition was but
number two is SQL injection isn't dead
smuggling queries at the protocol level
um which was a a Defcon talk and write
up by PS Paul um and essentially the
concept behind this one was um applying
James kettle's sort of hgp desync
research to different protocols and holy
crap dude
like really James changed the world with
that HB desync uh research in the first
place because it inspires crazy stuff
like this um so what what this guy PS
Paul did here was he investigated um
postgress
[__] um MySQL and and a bunch of other
sort of database um protocols and sort
of investigated what's going on there
and is there some way that we uh can
smuggle uh data in at the binary
protocol level the the protocol level
where the you know programming language
is communicating with the SQL Server um
in order to get sort of a smuggling sort
of scenario and uh the way he did this
is by manipulating these uh binary
protocol delimiters or ter or
Terminators right so there's a couple
main ways that he outlines in the in the
article and in the talk on on how these
binary Protocols are sort of structured
one a lot of times they have NES which
are like the terminating characters um
two sometimes they have length based
format so you you'll read like um you'll
read like a couple bytes and it'll be
like okay the following 100 bytes or
whatever are the payload so consider
that to be the payload and then it reads
100 bytes and then it's like another
type delineator another length and then
the payload right and you can kind of
get data across that
way and and that's kind of what happened
with these with these uh database binary
protocols is they they would have a
length which was an integer and then
they would have you know a set of data
and what the researcher found and what
all of this boils down to essentially is
integer overflows in the libraries that
are interacting with uh these SQL
servers so specifically an integer
overflow in the length part portion of
these binary protocols so if you send
just an absolutely massive payload
through to this SQL Server you know 4
gigabytes about 4 gigabytes what'll
happen is the integer will overflow and
become a really small integer for the
length right so when it goes to read the
message it only reads like the first
couple characters of the message and
then the data that then comes after that
is no longer data but it's actually a
part of the binary protocol and then if
you can structure it properly which he
gave some cool tips on doing then you
can actually smuggle full uh SQL queries
into this binary protocol and induce you
know arbitrary SQL statements which is
kind of like sort of a stacked query
sort of um SQL injection sort of
scenario is this is is there like a
basically a noop sled just like a
traditional buffer overflow like CU if
you're sending a 4 gigabyte thing and
somewhere in there there's going to be
something you want it to execute but
it's probably quite small like a like a
single query would be tiny right so I
wonder if there's like the basically a
no opsed oh there is yeah crafting a
payload notled yeah yeah an upled um of
that for sure and and they actually had
a similar sort of concept in there that
wasn't exactly an upled um but it it was
sort of similar for the binary protocol
itself um so yeah that was really cool
really awesome research here and one
little tidbit about 27 minutes into the
video was um a section that was entitled
uh tips for sending big data to web apps
okay and I thought that was so valuable
because he kind of gives a couple tips
here that says okay when you're dealing
with sending 4 gigabytes to a web app
like it takes a lot of time and a lot
you know you expect some component along
the way to sort of fail and he gives
advice right and so he gives some advice
for for getting around it and one of the
ones that I thought was great was just
use compression uh if the web server
that's parsing it on the back end you
know let's say you've got engine X in
front of like a web server right it
engine X is only going to look at the
content length before it freaks out and
says I can't I can't deal with this big
payload right so if you can compress
your data via gzip and just send that in
like as a header and then send it
through
it's going to compress to something tiny
absolutely yeah 100% and uh and and so a
very repetitive data um and so using
that compression can allow you to get
through like layers of middleware um and
so that that applies to like the reverse
proxy sort of scenario but also to the
websocket scenario um because websockets
also have some uh Native compression
that are associated with a lot of the
servers that um host websockets um
connections so very cool um the other
two here the other two here were use
alternative body types so maybe send
like a um what's the so you got like X
form encoded you've got Json and then
there's like the mime uh I can't
remember the name of it multiart that's
what it is multiart forms yeah um
sometimes that has has bigger
limitations or um more generous
limitations on it and then also he said
try to find some way to do serers side
creation of this massive string you know
is there some way that you can run you
know some a programming language or
something where it will output a massive
string and store it in the database uh
if there is then you might be able to
use that to create this massive string
on the server side then you don't have
to worry about all of that sort of hgp
middleware um so I I I I think as as you
know larger payloads become more
impactful um and and have more of a
place in in web app testing you know as
this sort of demonstrated here I think
those tips are going to be really really
valuable so could the payload I assumed
based on the when I read it that it had
to be like kind of like binary is data
like that you were like really
constructing some like uh unique
payloads but if he's saying you could
generate a big string server side via
some web app presumably there's some way
to do this with just like asky data
right or like unic code plus aski right
yeah yeah yeah presumably um I didn't
get just he didn't really elaborate on
that point but it would have to be
pretty granular the actual exploitation
piece but maybe you know a smaller piece
could be um very granular l l user
controlled and then you know the rest
could just be inflation of the data so
to speak that makes the Overflow occur
and then you know you sort of are
dealing with a smaller section of
actually functional data and that gets
executed before hitting all that junk
which just causes the server to ignore
the rest of it yeah so very very cool
stuff there I wonder the last time SQL
injection was a top three in any or top
two for example in any uh Port sger top
10 it's probably been a
yeah SQL in I mean this is he says SQL
injection I don't even this isn't I
don't know what this is but uh it's not
quite SE the normal SQL injection all
righty man number one we got confusion
attacks this is orange and it and it's
yours it's not mine and I'm glad because
it looks complex but what have we got
here yeah so basically like usual orange
went super deep on something in this
case instead of it being Unicode
specifically the the the big thing you
know the the the big key Point here that
unlocks a lot of this is the question
mark and so um I think that some hacker
needs to make it through identity to
basically be like the Joker from the
very old Batman with the question marks
all over it you know like that needs to
be your stick we we need some uh some
Buck Hunter to like make that their
stick but
um but yeah I mean he goes into extreme
extreme depth but the point of it is
that the there's a lot of middleware you
know again we're really looking at
secondary context here it's a lot of re
right rules it's a lot of enginex rules
um and some of them are really
interesting and it makes me want to do
exactly what we're just talking about
right use that HTTP Garden to kind of
see how these get handled differently um
and it always makes me wish I could be
omnicient and just look at the config
files across like all the bug bnny
programs to like grab for like this
specific string like are there rewrite
rules with dollar son one right because
it's rewriting that little path so yeah
let me um I'll share my screen but dude
it's crazy whenever I I see these write
ups like this and the payload is so
simple he's like yeah and then I just
put percent 3F in there and just like
what yes then just the right in the
right just the right place and so it's
always like really hard to know if if if
he came to it top down or bottom up it's
like is he checking everything and he
happens to find these one things or is
he at the bottom standing these up doing
code review and finding them from from
you know the bottom up probably probably
more the lad but um but yeah super
interesting stuff right um basically the
issue is that there's like you know
weird replaces that are going on with
these rewrite rules that allow you to to
kind of Pop these different
vulnerabilities um and and scroll scroll
down a little bit on this the one that
blows my mind is at the bottom here
right right at the bottom of your screen
right there with the server upload it it
it says curl server upload one. GI and
inside the GIF you know there's a
there's a a PHP payload and then he just
adds to the end of that payload uh
percent 3F o. PHP and then it renders as
a as a PHP file and I'm like oh my God
this is nuts yeah so genius right and
I'm sure some of us try a little things
like this here and there but it seems
like orange knows exactly where to try
it he's hunting with um with actual like
full vision and the rest of us are
hunting hunting blind um but um yeah so
there's a bunch of cool stuff in here I
I wrote down a few different things one
is um on the path truncation part so um
there's a bunch of different um like
Primitives where you know paths are
getting truncated because of the percent
3F
I was going to ask you if you remember
when you looked at this or if there if
you have like some sort of sniffer like
whenever you're testing like what is
your smell for if a truncation is
actually occurring because I think
there's so many times whenever you put a
encoded character like percent 3F per o
perc o a and it just like 400s or 404s
in like in like a weird way and my
inclination I I have a hard time knowing
if that's interesting or not sometimes
I'll continue looking at it sometimes I
won't and because like if it's
interpreting percent like let's just say
it's percent 2f so it's I'm you know I'm
using a slash or and I'm throwing in
some percent 2 e if it's not ever being
normalized on the back end then of
course it would 404 because who's gonna
name their file space SL space slash
right and so um and so anyways I didn't
know if you had some advice or some
practical kind of like takeaways that
would that helps you whenever you're in
those situations yeah to be honest dude
I mean as a client side hacker I
actually look at this sort of thing a
lot right like path normalization and
like trying to smuggle past checks like
this is is super helpful and you know
orange uses it here more in in a client
side perspective but um there's a lot of
scenarios where if the client if the
server will parse a percent 2f like a
raw percent 2f not like a a um a decoded
percent 2f as like a path delimiter
that's a crazy Gadget and and so same
thing with like the percent 3F right
question mark if if it is truncating the
path at that specific point and and that
is becoming a
then that is a major Gadget in your in
your toolkit and actually I definitely
I'm going to add it to my to-do list
right now for kaido because I really
want to create a little kaido plugin is
super easy with workflows um plugin to
detect these sort of things right
because it should be super easy to just
send slash you know to one of them and
then percent to F and if you get the
same response back then it's parsing
percent to f as a as a slash yeah you
know um and and same same thing with
like uh the now it's trying my to-do
this app is is parsing the percent as a
uh as a
label um but yeah it's it's uh it's a
very easy Gadget to identify and uh it
has so many different purposes across
all of the uh the application um and
it's pretty common I think I found it
many times yeah exactly yeah I mean it
doesn't surprise me at all whenever I
have a server that interprets percent to
f as a slash like you said it's yeah
yeah very common um so I mean obviously
this is extremely deep we're not going
to go through all of it imp I but one
thing that I talked with you about
before we went live that I thought was
really interesting was this Sim link um
I think it's actually easy to find if
you go to symbolic link so I'm gonna
read a little bit of this and then
Justin can break it down or I or I can
or I can break it down as well but I was
I was really curious about uh this
section right here so it says to wrap up
our jailbreak primitive let's showcase
how to perform an rce using a double hop
symbolic link and so one that just
sounds really cool but two what a badass
right exactly uh but but two I was like
kind of confused how it worked and so um
you know here is his final payload and
then here are the two SIM links that
he's showing you exist in order to get
to this payload so do you mind to break
down how this works yeah yeah I so the
takea away from this that I got was
depending on the configuration in Apache
and hbd um it will follow Sim links and
sometimes you're locked into a specific
directory because of where the the um
document route is or or where this thing
is is U pointing back to um but there's
this really handy thing called Sim links
that will allow you to just jump into
different directories and then you know
when when you're in an environment where
um there are very far nested folders and
and sink sort of nested down like there
was in this specific instance for red
mine um you can kind of chain those
together so hit a Sim link now you're in
a different directory find a Sim Link in
that directory hit that Sim link and now
you're in a different directory and then
you can you know go down until you find
uh in this scenario he he was able to
leak a secret key um so it's just a
gadget for getting access to documents
that are in a different directory that
you're not normally scop to because at
the end of the day all these traditional
web servers like um enginex and Apache
all they are is just exposing the file
system right VI over HTTP um and that's
kind of what he's taken advantage of
here is using a sort of a file system um
technique right uh symbolic links and
and utilizing that to jump around within
the file system even that's that's
outside of his uh scope directory yeah
so in this case the secret key lives
inside of etsy redmine default and so we
don't have we don't have access to that
so then he was able to basically go to
um you know you want to get here so you
go to VAR lib redmine config and that's
why this config is here because VAR lib
redmine gets overwritten by this Sim
link so you actually browse to this one
place that you have access to which is
uh you know HTML user share red mine
instances and then that gets overwritten
to VAR lib redmine this is impossible to
represent in an audio format so sorry
for anyone listening on YouTube that are
that are trying to follow with this
there's like several Sim links um that
and essentially it just uh dumps US in a
directory where there's there's access
to secret stuff so yeah and I guess the
big take away for anyone listening in
audio is that I just never knew this was
really possible at like a HTML web web
app level like of course whenever you're
whenever you like get code execution in
a sandbox you're trying to escape you're
looking for siming you're doing this
like this is like very normal stuff but
I did not realize that you could
basically construct a massive URL that
included you know to a web app that
actually included like a double s link
hop like this very interesting stuff
very interesting and it does require I
I'll read this this part right here it
says in debting ubun to distributions of
htpd the follow Sim links option is
explicitly enabled by default love it
but even in non Deb and yunu versions H
Apache HTP server also implicitly allows
Sim uh allows symbolic links by default
and then it provides a very common uh
Apache snippet that I've seen time and
time again with the options follow Sim
links um uh directive so uh ve very cool
stuff there um definitely going to keep
that in mind if I'm ever sort of in that
environment where I'm scoped to a a
specific directory and try have access
to the file system to find these
symbolic links yep um and so then the
next thing that I was going to mention
about this was that orange just makes me
wish I had like five times more time to
sink into like a single thing instead of
like being like really spread out and so
you know I know that obviously you do
that on specific programs that we both
kind of do that especially on like when
it comes to a live hacking event but
it's really interesting the way that um
he sits down into a really deep uh well
of of knowledge like a very a really
deep well of a single application you
know and then all the implications that
can kind of arise from that and does a
great job of like stuff that's going to
have really you know cross um user cross
company impact so pretty cool yeah very
good stuff man um did you did you see
this last thing right here where he's
like writing an HTTP request raw that
that's crazy where is it arbitary
Handler tar the thing you're actually on
right now with the sharing sharing your
screen yeah yeah yeah this was crazy
this this like when when we reviewed it
before I talked a little bit about this
but the first time I actually came
across this it's in the dock I actually
grabbed the link before we started um
was fron actually doing a write up on
enginex middleware misconfigurations and
essentially uh what what he was
describing in that scenario is a a
enginex configuration where you can just
start putting in new line characters in
there like percent OD percent o AA yeah
and drop a new line and then just
rebuild the whole HP request on the back
end before it reaches the uh you know
the backend server um and I think those
are so cool I really really do I've
never found one and I would love to find
one uh being able to just rewrite the
whole backend request um but orange also
does that here with some Apache
configurations yeah I feel like there's
a bunch there's like not a bunch there's
been a couple different cases where you
get this opportunity to do this um one I
think is like kind of the request
smuggling you can sometimes like you
know you can sometimes like write an
entire request that then's going to kind
of get parsed um and then I think maybe
it was Eric today as new sent me like a
uh wow I wonder if it was maybe actually
this um before then I'm going to try to
find the um exact vulnerability that we
were exploiting at the time and see if
it is relevant to this but I remember
specifically that it had an encoded
question mark in the G parameter and
then we would then we built an entire
request with other with other characters
and then it was actually getting
executed and it was uh it did not have a
curl payload like this it wasn't like I
don't think it was code execution in the
same way that this location is this
request here but um it definitely did
involve making like it ended up being an
ssrf of some sort and so I'll try to
look that up because it was really
interesting wow yeah there's there's
lots of these across I think multiple
environments and it doesn't just affect
Apache like he's talking about here
there's also um this in engine X as well
as France pointed out so we'll link that
that um that blog post in the
description even though it's on
detectify domain uh so yeah don't don't
love detectify anymore but the research
is still good so check it out sweet yeah
and then the one last thing you know you
you may have something else but the one
thing I wanted to mention from this uh
that even you know that this
specifically and many more in here
basically bring to my mind is that we
work in the best freaking industry like
the fact that this is real life that
this is real security research that we
get to actually I mean it's just so cool
right and we get to exploit these uh and
you know find cool vulnerabilities that
we get to talk about and that we get to
teach about and I think that we work in
the best industry and so I just wanted
to mention that dude it's so it's so
engaging like literally yesterday I was
standing right there you know right in
front of my fireplace here jumping up
and down screaming like hugging my buddy
because we popped a crazy bug um and
it's just like wow this is my job you
know like some people go to work and
they put in their eight hours and they
come home you know and that's it you
know they they don't like their job but
I get to sit here and scream and jump up
and down and have this like amazing
dopamine Rush when you when you uh when
you find a bug so it's pry sick dude
yeah and it's having this massive impact
like I was just talking today with uh
Kier on the guest from the previous
episode and uh because he's interested
in potentially like chasing down a tedex
talk and we were just like workshopping
some ideas and and you know one idea
that I brought up is it's just like bug
bounty has had an unfathomable amount of
impact on the total security of the
internet at large like I think that the
hacker one report IDs which obviously
there's lots of Naas lots of information
lots of
but is over 3 million and I'm sure that
bug crowd Integrity these other large
platforms have very similar like you
know report num so we're we're I think
we're approaching probably 10 millions
in the IDS but that is not even close to
counting the amount of like when a SAS
vulnerability gets fixed it gets fixed
for all tenants right when a zero when a
zero day gets when a zero day gets found
and patch in a library and how many
vulnerabilities are in libraries sdks
you know plugins so many right so we're
probably talking on the order of tens of
millions if not hundreds of millions of
vulnerabilities that have been found as
a result of like the hard work of bug
Hunters like us and I think that's
really cool dude hell yeah dude that's
what I'm talking about give me some
right now give me a fist bump through
the podcast right now all right guys
well hey that's it that's a wrap on the
port swier top 10 congratulations on
being in the best industry in the world
at least at least we think that's what
it yeah I definitely think so yeah and
uh keep keep getting those bugs y'all
all right peace that's the Pod and
that's a wrap on this episode of
critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us we'll see you there